https://www.puntiantichi.com/policy/eng_informativa_estesa.html

Privacy Policy - Informativa Estesa sull'Uso dei Cookie
Privacy Policy - Cookie Policy
CookieS Policy
This site uses cookies and in some cases third-party cookies to provide a better experience and service for users.
When navigating or using our services you agree to our use of cookies.
However, the user has the option to prevent the generation of cookies and disposal of the same by selecting the appropriate option in your browser. If you block the use of cookies on your browser it may disrupt some services and some functions of the website may not be available.
What is a cookie?
A cookie is a small piece of text that websites send to the browser and is stored on the user's terminal, which may be a personal computer, a mobile phone, a tablet, etc. These files allow the website to remember information about your visit, such as language and preferred options, which can make your next visit easier and make the site more useful for you.
Cookies play a very important role in improving user experiences on the web.
How are cookies used?
By browsing this website you are accepting that we can install cookies on your machine and let us know the following information:
Statistical information on the user's use of the web.
The user 'login' which keeps the session active on the web.
The preferred format of web access from mobile devices.
Latest searches over web services and data customisation services.
Information about the ads that are displayed to the user.
Information from surveys that the user has participated in.
Data connection to social networks for users, accessing your Facebook or Twitter.
Types of cookies used
This website uses both temporary session cookies and persistent cookies.
Session cookies store information only while the user accesses the Web and persistent cookies stored in the terminal data to be accessed and used in more than one session.
Technical cookies
These allow the user to navigate through the website or application and use the various options or services there.
For example, with traffic control and data communication, to identify the session, access restricted Web parts, remember the elements of an order, make the request for registration or participation in an event, use the security features during navigation, and store content for broadcast video or sound.
Cookies customisation
These allow users to access the service with some predefined general features in your terminal, or user defined settings. For example, the language, the type of browser through which you access the service, the design of selected content, geolocation terminal and place where you can access the service.
Advertising cookies
These allow the effective management of advertising spaces which are included in the Web page or application from which the service is provided. They allow the adaptation of advertising for it to be relevant to the user and to avoid showing ads that the user has already seen.
Statistical analysis cookies
These allow the monitoring and analysis of user behavior on websites. The information gathered through such cookies is used in measuring the activity of web, application or platform sites and the profiling of user navigation of these sites, in order to make improvements to the service and functionality for users.
Third Party Cookies
On some web pages you can install third-party cookies allow you to manage and improve the services offered.
For example, the statistical services of Google Analytics.
When you use our website, you may also be sent third party cookies.
Our advertisers and service providers may send you cookies.
They may use the information they obtain from your use of their cookies:
to track your browser across multiple websites
to build a profile of your web surfing
to target advertisements which may be of particular interest to you.
In addition to the information we provide in this Cookie Policy, you can find out more information about your online choices at http://www.youronlinechoices.co.uk
How to manage cookies in the browser?
The user has the option to allow, block or delete cookies installed on your computer by setting your browser options installed on your terminal:
To set the permissions associated with cookies on Google Chrome Browser:
Click the menu in the toolbar.
Select Configuration.
Click Show advanced options.
In the "Privacy" section click the Content Settings button.
In the section "Cookies" there are configurable options.
To set the permissions related to cookies in Mozilla Firefox Browser:
At the top of the Firefox window click the Tools menu.
Select Options.
Select the Privacy panel.
You can choose 'use custom settings' to configure.
To set the permissions related to browser cookies in Internet Explorer 9:
At the top of the Internet Explorer window click on the Tools menu.
Select the Security tab and use the Delete Browsing History to delete cookies. Enable Cookies check box, and then click Delete.
Select the Security tab, and use the settings to move the slider to the top to block all cookies or totally down to allow all cookies. After that, click OK.
If you block the use of cookies on your browser it may disrupt some services or functionality of the website may be reduced.
For further information about how to refuse cookies, please refer to your browser ‘Help’ section or see www.allaboutcookies.org.
Some browsers can be configured to manage specific cookie rules for different websites, which provides more precise control over privacy.
This means you can disable cookies for all sites except those in which you trust.
What is online behavioural advertising/ interest based advertising?
Online behavioural advertising (also known as interest-based advertising) is a way of serving advertisements on the websites you visit and making them more relevant to you and your interests.
Shared interests are grouped together based upon previous web browsing activity and web users are then served advertising which matches their shared interests. In this way, advertising can be made as relevant and useful as possible. Relevant ads can also be delivered based upon the website content you have just been viewing. This is known as ‘retargeting’.
There are a number of sites which can help you opt out of online behavioural advertising from the third party advertising agencies that operate online behavioural advertising for website publishers.
These include http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/ and http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices.
COOKIES Used on the site
Warning: Some features and sections of our site are accessible only by enabling cookies.
We make use of different service providers (Google, Facebook, Twitter) that, in order to provide their services, can put cookies on your browser when you visit our site.
We strive to identify these cookies before they are used in order to allow you to decide whether you want to accept them or not.
Additional information regarding these cookies may be available on the website of the third party.
For more information about third-party cookies and how to use the information collected by the third party, use the links below or contact the relevant third party.
Cookies that may be placed and / or read by third parties when using the site
Name
Typology
Purpose and description of cookies
WordPress Cookies
Navigation Cookies
Cookies have the exclusive function to recognize logged in users, allowing your viewing even in restricted areas.
Joomla Cookies
Navigation Cookies
Cookies have the exclusive function to recognize logged in users, allowing your viewing even in restricted areas.
VBulletin Cookies
Navigation Cookies
Cookies have the exclusive function to recognize logged in users, allowing your viewing even in restricted areas. Apart from this, there are also session cookies for the proper functioning of the Forum.
Kunena Cookies
Navigation Cookies
Cookies have the exclusive function to recognize logged in users, allowing your viewing even in restricted areas. Apart from this, there are also session cookies for the proper functioning of the Forum.
MediaWiki Cookies
Navigation Cookies
Cookies have the exclusive function to recognize logged in users, allowing your viewing even in restricted areas. Apart from this, there are also session cookies for the proper functioning of the Wiki.
Performance Cookies
Navigation Cookies
Cookies have the function to save information on inline style sheets to speed up subsequent user visits and provide a faster and less expensive browsing.
Google (Analytics)
Third Party Cookies
This site uses this kind of web analytics service provided by Google Inc. for aggregate statistical information type useful to evaluate the use of the website and the activities carried out by the visitor. Google stores the information collected by the cookie on servers that can be located in the United States. Google reserves the right to transfer the information produced by its cookies to third parties where required by law or if the third party process information on its behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google in order to get a more detailed user profile. Additional information on the management of privacy and / or how to reject or delete this type of cookies are available at URL: http://www.google.it/intl/it/analytics/privacyoverview.html.
You can selectively disable the action of installing Google Analytics on your browser component of the opt-out provided by Google. To disable the collection of data from Google Analytics, please refer to the link below: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
You can opt out of interest-based ads by Google through Ads Settings. When you opt out, you’ll still see ads but they may not be related to factors such as your interests, previous visits to other websites, or demographic details. Visit: www.google.it/settings/ads.
Google (Analytics)
Third Party Cookies
__utma
Persistent cookie that keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site pertaining to the cookie, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred. Google Analytics uses the information from this cookie to calculate things like Days and Visits to purchase. __utmb and __utmc working together to calculate how long a visit takes. __utmb takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor enters a site, while __utmc takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor leaves a site. __utmb expires at the end of the session. __utmc waits 30 minutes, and then it expires.
__utmz keeps track of where the visitor came from, what search engine he used, what link he clicked on, what keyword he used, and where they were in the world when he accessed a website. It expires in 6 months. This cookie is how Google Analytics knows to whom and to what source / medium / keyword to assign the credit for a Goal Conversion or an Ecommerce Transaction. __utmz also lets you edit its length with a simple customization to the Google Analytics Tracking code. __utmv
gets set on the person’s computer, so that Google Analytics knows how to classify that visitor. The __utmv cookie is also a persistent, lifetime cookie.
Read more on Google Privacy policy
Embedded Content
Third Party Cookies
To enhance the user experience, we sometimes embed content from websites such as Facebook and YouTube. Pages with this embedded content may present cookies from their websites.
Similarly, when you use one of the share buttons on a website, a cookie may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about such cookies.
Facebook https://www.facebook.com/help/cookies/
Twitter https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en
Youtube https://www.google.it/intl/it/policies/privacy/
Google+ http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/
Vimeo https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy
Google
Third Party Cookies
(PREF) Stores information that change the behavior or appearance of the sites themselves, as your preferred language or region. (NID) Google may place these cookies if you press the button Google +1 - Google Privacy Policy
Google+
Third Party Cookies
Google Cookies Policy - Managing:  http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/managing/
Twitter
Third Party Cookies
(guest_id) (pid) Twitter leaves these cookies if you use the "Twitter" button on our website. Twitter Privacy Policy
Youtube (Google)
Third Party Cookies
(YSC) (VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE) Sometimes we may embed videos from YouTube. This may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. Google Privacy Policy
Facebook
Third Party Cookies
Sharing content on Facebook can set a cookie. For more information please review the
Facebook Privacy Policy - Facebook Cookies Policy
To configure access to your account. Section privacy.
LinkedIn
Third Party Cookies
LinkedIn Cookie Policy Configuration: https://www.linkedin.com/settings/
Pinterest
Third Party Cookies
The "Pin it" button and social widgets of Pinterest are interaction services with the Pinterest platform, provided by Pinterest Inc.
Personal data collected: Cookies and Data for use.
http://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy
CrazyEgg
Third Party Cookies
The site occasionally uses these cookies to optimize the web pages of your site by analyzing the movements of the users anonymously within the site.
https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy. Opt-out instruction: https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out
DoubleClick
Third Party Cookies
Our site to show the banners inside the pages makes use of third-party service DoubleClick. The service is used in a basic way, and therefore without any type of behavioral analysis. For more information on cookies in question used the following link http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/.
NewRelic
Third Party Cookies
The Web site to improve the user experience of the site by users and improve performance using an instrument called RUM NewRelic. For information about cookies of this instrument here is the link https://docs.newrelic.com/docs/browser/new-relic-browser/page-load-timing-resources/new-relic-cookies.
Google Fonts
Third Party Cookies
The site makes use in some parts of the fonts from the Google Fonts. For information about cookies in question here is the link https://www.google.it/intl/it/policies/privacy/
Cloudflare
Third Party Cookies
The Site uses as DNS Cloudflare. The service provides on-demand options of security and speeding up site that could be activated when delivering cookies to work properly. For information about cookies in question here is the link https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy
Adsense Ads
Regarding Google and its tools such as Google Analytics and Google Adsense advertising platform, more information on how to disable cookies and set your navigation preferences are available at the following links: http://www.google.com/goodtoknow/online-safety/security-tools/
http://www.google.com/intl/it/policies/privacy/
Amazon Ads
In reference to Amazon.it and any advertisements on the site you are visiting, the terms relating to privacy and cookie management are present at the following links:
http://www.amazon.it/gp/help/customer/display.html/?ie=UTF8&*Version*=1&*entries*=0&nodeId=201149100
https://www.amazon.it/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=200545460
“ShareThis” buttons and social widgets by ShareThis (Sharethis Inc)
ShareThis is a service that displays a widget that allows interaction with external social networks and platforms and sharing of content of this site.
Depending on the configuration, this service can show widget belonging to third parties, such as the managers of the social networks on which share interactions. In this case, the third parties that provide the widget will be made aware of the interaction and data usage on the pages where this service is installed.
Personal data collected: Cookie and data usage.
Place of treatment: USA – Privacy Policy - http://www.sharethis.com/legal/privacy/#sthash.oNiQUPLd.dpbs
Disabling other companies interest based ads
Opting out doesn’t stop interest-based ads that aren’t served by Google. So, when you browse the Internet and see a website, video, or app that’s outside of Google’s Display Network, you may still see interest-based ads from other companies.
What to do: Find a cross-industry opt out tool or control that works for your browser or device, like Aboutads.info or Online Choices (for European users).
The links above could became obsolete (not dependent on us).
The same information is, however, easily found using a search engine.
